(Respect copyright)
♪Memories hold you back
from fulfilling your dreams♪
♪Only by moving forward
can you find reunion♪
♪Endings only mark new routes♪
♪It's all part of the scenery♪
♪To the horizon's call♪
♪Your journey hasn't started♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Let time embrace you
and wash away the past♪
♪Put every twist behind you♪
♪Drift leisurely through time♪
♪Make headway against the wind♪
♪Let mountains bow to your pace♪
♪Rush towards a life without regret♪
♪Let your nature burst free♪
=The First Jasmine=
=Episode 12=
But before they reached the capital,
the late emperor passed away.
You should know about it as well.
I heard that they wanted
to take him away and crown him emperor.
Do you really think a dozen or so people
could install a new emperor?
You abducted the crown prince's son.
You're all ill-disposed,
and your crime is punishable by death.
Seize them!
(The fire in the Eastern Palace
was suspicious.)
(Mo Jingli, as the sole son
of the late crown prince,)
(would face danger
upon returning to the capital.)
(With his consent, they decided)
(to send him to Duke Hua's barracks
for temporary shelter.)
(However, Marquis Muyang bent the truth
and intercepted them halfway.)
(He then falsely charged them
with abducting Mo Jingli and rebellion.)
I remember many officials doubted it
at that time.
Duke Hua took the lead
in speaking up for them.
Yes, many had doubts.
Marquis Muyang
couldn't fully convict them.
He could only imprison them.
But when things were at a stalemate,
Mo Jingli suddenly came forward
and identified them.
He was only 14 at the time.
He was so young,
and I understand he was afraid.
(Testimony)
I can also
imagine the methods
Marquis Muyang would use to coerce him.
But I cannot forgive.
(Mo Jingli)
Those disciples all died that year.
The oldest among them was 24,
(Mo Jingli)
and the youngest was only 12.
Why are you suddenly telling me this?
I just want to tell you
that there is nothing
between Mo Jingli and me.
Even if he hadn't ended the engagement,
I would never have married him.
There were many snakes
at the bottom of the cliff,
as thick as a bowl mouth.
They kept circling me,
and no matter what, they wouldn't leave.
I knew you would come to save me.
So I kept dealing with them.
But I got bitten.
I passed out.
I'm sorry.
It's not your fault.
You couldn't help it.
Your Highness,
may I ask you for one thing?
What is it?
I want to help treat your leg injury.
Will you let me try?
Your Highness, just do it for my sake.
You and I met in the desert back then.
How brave and mighty you were.
Now, because of this injury,
you are confined to this chair
and powerless to fight back
against those evil people.
I don't want you like that.
You can consider me vain
or worldly.
Anyway, in my heart,
Your Highness is an indomitable hero.
I cannot bear, nor can I stand by
and watch you give up on yourself.
It can't be cured.
It can be cured.
Your Highness, let me try.
I promise it will definitely be cured.
Please, just let me give it a try.
(Upright and Principled)
Who's there?
Who's outside?
Go away.
(A heartless man is terrified at night,
with a ghost hanging from the beam)
Your Highness.
This soup helps you sober up.
After you finish the soup,
go to bed early.
Your Highness,
please don't drink anymore.
Your Highness, be careful.
Your Highness, what are you doing?
Your Highness.
Your Highness, please go inside quickly.
It's raining too hard outside.
Leave me alone. I'm not going back.
If Mo Jingli doesn't come,
I won't go inside.
Your Highness, you...
I'll go find His Highness now.
Mo Jingli, I hate you.
My mom is right.
The men in the capital are all bad.
They seem good yet bad inside.
Ling'er went to prepare your medicine.
I won't take it.
I don't even want to live anymore.
Why should I still take medicine?
Stop right there.
Do not leave.
Let's put it all on the table.
How could you treat me like this?
You can write a few poems,
so you think you're great?
You can compose, but so what?
Careful.
Don't touch me.
When I was at home,
I was loved by my family.
My mom doted on me.
My father also favored me.
Even Ye Li, as prominent as she was,
couldn't bully me.
So why did I end up like this
after getting married?
I looked forward to marrying you.
You are a man.
If you don't like a woman,
don't marry her.
If you marry her,
you should treat her well.
On our wedding day,
I was originally very happy.
But my happiness lasted only one day.
I hate you.
(I hate you.)
(You really haven't changed one bit.)
Prince Li.
When you say these words,
don't you find yourself ridiculous?
(They all died because of you.)
(I am one of Lishan Academy.)
(I can never forgive you.)
(You should be glad
you broke off our engagement.)
(Otherwise, I might lose control
and kill you on our wedding day.)
(You hate me.)
(You detest me.)
(You think I wanted things this way?)
(I detest myself too.)
Your Highness.
Your Highness, don't be sad.
Lady Ye Li is surely angry
about what happened back then.
She didn't know your situation before.
One day, when she finds out,
she'll definitely understand you.
Really?
Will she?
She will.
Right.
Li will understand.
She has always understood me best.
Caught it?
Caught it. Look.
Probably because I was the son
of the crown prince,
during those years in the academy,
everyone was absolutely polite to me
but kind of distant from me.
Only Li
was like the first ray of sunlight
breaking through the clouds,
pure and ardent.
In that moment,
I realized light actually has warmth.
We were inseparable all day long.
We played together.
We studied
and learned the guqin together.
She would teach me everything
she learned from the tutors.
And every time she left the mountain,
she would buy me many things.
Then later, my grandfather
arranged a marriage for me and Ye Li.
But those most wonderful times
will never come again.
(Lishan Academy)
(The Fourteenth Year of the Jinghe Era)
In the 14th year of the Jinghe era,
dire news came from the capital.
My grandfather was ill.
So I hurried back to the capital.
By the time I arrived at the palace,
my grandfather had already passed away.
The Eastern Palace,
which was once at its zenith,
was also burned to scorched ruins
in a great fire.
The past glory felt like a dream.
Upon waking, I found all traces gone.
Only the faction of Guo Jin
held overwhelming power.
As the son of the late crown prince,
I was confined.
From then on, I never saw Li again.
(First Year of the Xide Era)
Soon after, Mo Xiuwen was in trouble.
Guo Jin's ambition to ascend the throne
was abundantly clear.
Yet she failed because Lishan was shut,
and court officials opposed it.
She stayed calm and changed her mind.
- She placed Mo Yanqi on the throne.
- Bow!
- Long live the emperor!
(Jingsi Palace)
Three years
after Mo Yanqi ascended the throne,
I finally walked out of Jingsi Palace.
I became a decorative prop
to showcase her benevolence.
I was lucky.
Your Highness.
I survived.
My grandfather is dead.
My father is dead.
Even those brothers I hated
are all dead.
Only I survived.
I'm the emblem of her benevolence.
I am the pet of this imperial city,
the laughingstock of the capital.
Whatever she wants to hear,
I'll say it to her.
Whatever she wants to see,
I'll do it for her.
Dignity means nothing to me.
As long as I'm alive,
I still have a chance.
I can still see Li again.
But things didn't go as I wished.
What?
You cannot marry Lady Ye Li.
How dare you!
You've finally
gained the Empress Dowager's trust.
You should draw a clear line
with Lishan.
You cannot marry her.
How dare you!
Have you forgotten the fire
in the Eastern Palace?
Won't you avenge your father?
Your Highness.
Even if you don't consider yourself,
think of Lady Ye Li.
Though her days
are hard, she is not in mortal danger.
If you successfully ascend the throne,
it's the best.
But if you fail,
you'll be doomed, Your Highness.
Why drag her down with you?
Once Your Highness successfully
ascends the throne in the future,
you can then marry her
and crown her as the Empress.
Wouldn't that be better?
But I never expected
that Guo Jin would actually betroth Li
to Prince Ding.
Your Highness.
Time to drink the nuptial wine.
My life has been full of misfortunes.
I've never been able to get what I want.
Fate has never been kind to me.
But I refuse to accept such a fate.
Prince Li?
Sit.
You investigated the weaponry case.
Was Marquis Muyang behind it?
Yes.
Marquis Muyang trafficked in weapons.
He is a parasite of the nation.
I will definitely
bring a parasite like him to justice.
You're a good official,
concerned with the nation.
But now is not the time.
Kill all the useless ones.
Yes.
If you want something,
fight for it yourself.
I have no choice but to walk this path.
And I will never regret it.
Only in this way
can I protect myself,
the former followers of my father,
and Li.
Your Highness.
One day,
you will ascend the throne.
You will obtain everything you desire.
(Prince Ding's Mansion)
You want to treat His Highness's legs?
Yes.
His Highness's leg injury is treatable.
It just takes time.
I plan to start with the acupoints,
like Guanyuan, Qihai
(Zusanli)
Zusanli, and other points,
to dissolve the stagnant
and open the meridians with the needles.
After the meridians are opened,
we'll reset the bones.
His Highness's legs have atrophied now.
Your idea is right, indeed.
Removing stagnant blood is easy,
while opening the meridians is hard.
How will you do, Your Highness?
What is this?
Don't be afraid.
This is a long needle,
one of the nine needles.
According to a medical book,
the long needle is sharp and thin.
It can treat chronic pain.
His highness's legs have atrophied
for eight years.
We need this needle
to pierce the Chengshan point
and the Weizhong point.
It can reduce pain in the waist
and strengthen the lower body.
He has stagnant blood in the waist.
I'll then use a silver needle
on the Shenshu point.
This opens the meridians
to circulate blood freely.
The toxins in the legs
will naturally be relieved.
♪Love is not just romance♪
♪They don't get my obsession♪
♪Why do two struggling souls make a vow♪
♪And stake everything♪
♪Hardship makes us sensible♪
♪Even with all these feelings,
we hold back♪
♪To live once more for each other♪
♪To become a better version
of ourselves♪
♪Love has never been just this.
Who knows♪
(Schedule)
♪If the soul comes with thorns♪
♪Embrace to feel♪
(Herbs)
♪Like friends
always standing side by side♪
♪Love is but a beginning,
knowing each other day and night♪
♪On such a long road,
holding hands and never letting go♪
♪Only then do we understand why love♪
♪Means more than one thing♪
♪The little and big things left
in each other's lives♪
♪Along the way,
we've skipped the explanation of love♪
♪Seeing a complete life♪
Go prepare the medicine.
Yes.
♪Love has never been just this.
Who knows♪
♪Nobody acknowledges your persistence♪
♪If the soul comes with thorns♪
Your Highness,
are His Highness's legs almost healed?
There is the most crucial step to go.
♪We always work together like friends♪
♪Love is but a beginning,
knowing each other day and night♪
(Jingzhao Prefecture)
♪Only then do we understand why love♪
♪Means more than one thing♪
You're reading the official documents?
You're quite busy.
You ban me from going to the office.
So I had no choice
but to bring work home.
The poultice is ready.
I can treat your legs now.
Your leg problem has been delayed long.
It needs to be re-broken and reset.
Breaking bones is very painful.
I know.
♪Love has never been just this,
I hope you know♪
I'm not afraid.
♪We understand when we trade places♪
So confident in me?
Since I let you treat me,
naturally, I trust you.
It's worth a try.
It can't get worse than now.
♪Love is but a beginning,
the pain is brief♪
♪On such a long road,
I hold your fingers♪
I will definitely cure you.
♪I haven't gotten it off my chest♪
(Marquis Muyang's Mansion)
(Great Ambition and Responsibility)
Two bandits slipped into the capital.
They killed four high-ranking officials.
One of them even died
within the imperial palace.
And Mo Xiuyao's closing report
actually says the bandits are at large.
He only issued a wanted notice.
He is treating all court officials
and me as a fool.
I can't stand this.
Master, don't be mad.
Previously, to catch Yuan Fang,
our men pretended to be bandits.
Mo Xiuyao is just copying us.
We should have eliminated him too.
I've been here for a while.
Your Majesty, what can I do for you?
Mo Xiuyao has gone too far!
Relying on His Majesty's favor,
he's getting bolder.
How did Yuan Fang die?
Your Majesty, I have stressed it before.
I didn't kill Yuan Fang.
All these years,
I've never concealed anything,
small or big, from Your Majesty.
I swear I'm absolutely loyal
to Your Majesty.
Fine, even if I believe your vow,
then why was Yuan Fang captured
in Huaixi?
He was ordered
to investigate the weaponry case.
And your family is based in Huaixi.
Bandits could take him away
from the government office.
Does this matter truly have nothing
to do with your family in Huaixi?
Do you really know nothing at all?
Your Majesty.
Lu Changfu and his men
brought it upon themselves.
I have warned you long ago
to manage your people well.
The emperor values Mo Xiuyao.
Whether he succeeds or fails
is his own thing.
But he cannot fail because of you.
Do you understand?
Your Majesty.
The medicine is ready.
You can drink it now, Your Majesty.
Marquis Muyang, you may leave.
Marquis Muyang,
do you still have something to say?
Your Majesty.
Now you despise me, seeing me
as a worthless thing.
Do you want to cast me aside?
Don't forget.
It was I who did everything I could
for you and eliminated your dissidents.
It was I who supported you consistently.
It was I who crushed the treacherous
and wiped out the villains for you.
Now, the nation is peaceful.
So, you want to discard me
once your purpose is served?
Are you crazy?
Shut up!
What?
You're offending Her Majesty recklessly.
Are you trying to rebel?
Your Majesty,
I'm absolutely loyal to you.
I merely feel aggrieved
and hard to calm.
I beg Your Majesty to discern clearly
and not believe slanderous words.
Otherwise, it will hurt me.
The weather is hot,
and you're a meat-lover.
That makes you irritable.
From now on, be a vegetarian.
(Xiangqi Pavilion)
Take care.
Well,
Your Highness, what are we doing here?
My lady, what can I do for you?
I'm here for Lady Yusheng.
Have you come to the wrong place?
Xiangqi Pavilion is a place of pleasure.
It is not a place for ordinary women.
Lady Yusheng and I are old friends.
Just show me the way.
Thank you, my lady.
My lady, here's Lady Yusheng's room.
Thank you.
Wait outside for me.
I'll come out shortly.
Yes.
Your surname is Ye?
Lady Ye, have some tea, please.
Lady Ye, how did you get to know Feibai?
How did we meet?
We grew up together.
Childhood sweethearts?
And how did you meet him?
At a banquet on the Shangsi Festival,
I was harassed by a drunkard.
I nearly fell into the lotus pond.
Fortunately, Feibai saved me.
He came under the moonlight.
He alone fought off the drunkard.
Then, with a light flick of his sword,
he retrieved my fallen hairpin
from the pond water.
Afterward, we wandered together
under the moonlight.
We made poems under an old ginkgo tree.
He said, "Do not say autumn frost
hastens the tree's aging."
I continued the verse, "Burn red leaves
to warm the cold washing stone."
What a lovely story.
Lady Ye, what brings you to seek Feibai?
You're finally back.
Why have you been leaving early
and returning late?
I've been busy lately.
Really? Could it be
because of some woman?
This is Princess Ding, Ye Li.
We went to the same academy.
She's married?
Turns out you're Princess Ding.
Please forgive my rudeness.
Yusheng, I need to talk to her alone.
Alright, I'll go prepare the meal.
The Yuzhen chicken here is good.
You can eat
once you've finished talking.
Don't tell anyone else she's here.
Don't worry.
When have I ever spoken of your things
to outsiders?
Go on.
What's with that look?
Nothing. Have you found Master Zhu?
I've searched all the inns, taverns,
and transport shops in the city.
I haven't found any trace of him.
Master Zhu said
he has a few old friends in the capital.
Could he be staying
at someone's house as well?
Did you go check?
Sure, but I didn't find him.
Li, when you fell off the cliff,
are you sure you saw Master Zhu?
Of course.
Didn't I tell you last time?
Where is Master Zhu hiding?
It's very dangerous
for him to be outside alone.
Don't worry. I'll keep looking.
Don't worry about this matter.
Well, you came here today,
not just to ask about Master Zhu, right?
I need your help.
What is it?
Mo Xiuyao agreed
to let me treat his legs.
You must help me.
(Marquis Muyang's Mansion)
Master.
Dowager Consort Qin is here.
Got it. You may leave.
Yes.
Why have you come?
What? Do you feel
that I made you lose face that day?
I wouldn't dare.
I was saving you.
Zhou Jing, we've been friends
for many years.
We've weathered storms together
and entrusted our lives to each other.
I can turn a blind eye
to what you've secretly been doing
for money.
I can even exonerate you.
But you must understand one thing.
The reason we can stand together
is that we are both
on the Empress Dowager's side.
I have always remembered that.
But what about the Empress Dowager?
Does she remember?
The emperor, to seize real power,
has killed many of my people.
Has the Empress Dowager seen this?
Even a cripple like Mo Xiuyao
bossed me around.
And how did the Empress Dowager respond?
Not only did she not stand up for me,
but she actually suspected me
because of Yuan Fang.
Yuan Fang was her trusted confidant.
He had never coveted power
before he died.
He had been loyal
with absolute devotion.
Why did you fight against a loyal man?
I didn't.
I only hope she won't pin the blame
for Yuan Fang's murder on me.
Fine.
Since you didn't kill him,
then find the real murderer.
If you don't clear yourself
of suspicion,
how can the Empress Dowager trust you
in the future?
How can you hold onto your position?
But those killed officials
were all loyal to me.
Lu Changfu and his rats deserved to die.
The pressing priority is
to regain the Empress Dowager's trust.
With her trust,
you'll have a good future.
(Pleasant and Calm)
This is Master Yunqi.
He is kind of a renowned physician
from Luoyang.
He began studying medicine at seven
and has practiced for over 20 years.
He is most skilled in orthopedics,
specializing in bone injuries.
Thank you.
Your Highness,
must the bones really be broken?
It'll unavoidably injure his body.
Don't worry.
My technique can avoid further injury.
I'll first use a fine needle
on the Qihai point.
When breaking the bone,
it won't harm the blood vessels.
But I'm not sure if Your Highness
can withstand this kind of pain.
I'm not afraid of pain.
I just don't know
if your technique is that good.
I've merely read some old medical books
and lack experience.
If I carelessly miss the acupoint,
I can only beg for your forgiveness.
You began studying medicine at seven.
You should know
that if the Qihai is injured,
it can cause lifelong paralysis.
You won't ruin your own reputation,
will you?
Master Yunqi just loves to joke.
If we delay any longer,
the anesthetic's effect will wear off.
Let's talk later.
♪Why do you panic♪
♪For no reason,
you pushed me away and left me♪
♪Afraid we might start again♪
♪Changing many things, right or wrong♪
♪Fate is blurred and bewildering♪
♪Are you also unwilling
to show weakness♪
♪To recover what was once taken♪
♪Our warmth will not be swallowed up♪
♪Amidst life's ups and downs,
turns and twists♪
♪Love has never strayed away♪
♪Throughout this lifetime♪
♪In the end, we're together again♪
♪Countless trials and pleadings,
right or wrong♪
♪Try to make this love quiet♪
♪But we fight back♪
♪To make it a tale to be told♪
♪Deepest love is none other than♪
♪Aligning my scars with yours♪
♪What was once let go♪
♪Will heal together from now on♪
♪From your silhouette♪
♪I see the same me♪
♪If dreams become illusions♪
♪With you I journey and find solace♪
♪In the sole abode of heart♪
♪We embrace and circle into a corner♪
(Tuisi Pavilion)
♪Love lightly brushes past♪
♪Like you, like me♪
♪The eyes are still clear♪
♪None better than you,
and none better than me♪
♪Love can last until the spring♪
♪Silently, we turn pain into joy♪
Don't chew. Hold it under your tongue.
This is a pain relief pill.
It needs to dissolve in the saliva.
♪So we can tightly fit together♪
♪Without you, there's no me♪
♪Passing by the world♪
♪Part of my broken self♪
♪Finds our places in an embrace♪
♪Fulfilling our wishes♪
♪Lovers remain calm and composed♪
♪Like you, like me♪
Are you feeling better now?
♪None better than you,
and none better than me♪
♪Love blooms at every spring and sunset♪
(Preview)
My parents used to call me Yao.
Yao.
I didn't expect you
to also be a master of Go.
Again.
I never imagined that you did that.
♪Memories hold you back
from fulfilling your dreams♪
♪Only by moving forward
can you find reunion♪
♪Endings only mark new routes♪
♪It's all part of the scenery♪
♪To the horizon's call♪
♪Your journey hasn't started♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Both joy and grief
make the trip worthwhile♪
♪Trying to catch up
to your own lost shadow♪
♪Within the wilds, echoes thrive♪
♪Clear mind leads to a clear path♪
♪Be grateful to your losses♪
♪Make your steps weightless♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Let time embrace you
and wash away the past♪
♪Put every twist behind you,
drift leisurely through time♪
♪Make headway against the wind,
let mountains bow to your pace♪
♪Rush towards a life without regret♪
♪Let your nature burst free♪
♪Unbound by form♪